## DANIEL KOLSI - SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER / CONSULTANT



+52 (1) 4443355132 kolsi.daniel@gmail.com

Skype: danielkolsi

Portfolio: <a href="https://danielkolsi.github.io/">https://danielkolsi.github.io/</a>

Project resume: https:// danielkolsi.github.io/ docs/resume.html

LinkedIN: https:// www.linkedin.com/in/ kolsi/

Developer story: <a href="https://danielkolsi.github.io/docs/ds.html">https://danielkolsi.github.io/docs/ds.html</a>

Current residence: San Luis Potosi, México

Marital status: married Nationality: Finnish (eligible to work anywhere in EU/UK)

Date & place of birth: 21.08.1975, Stockholm, Sweden

Languages: Finnish (native), English, Swedish, Spanish, German, Hebrew

#### **Profile**

A seasoned full-stack software professional with 20+ years of experience. I've served multiple international customers as a software consultant. Deep expertise from Java (JEE), Javascript (MEAN + ReactJS) and DevOps. Scrummaster certification and Android app development experience (published in Google Play). Lateral out-of-the box thinker with an ability to solve complex problems and to focus on essential. Strives to deliver and to increase ROI. A strong demoscene background from early 90s. Over 10 years of startup experience. I prefer agile development. How can I help you?

#### **Experience**

# owner / engineer, FaceOP (Finland + México), 2014-

Visioned and developed from scratch a full-stack app for profile matched face-to-face group meetings at Google Play (Android Java). Side-projects include ReactJS chess-solution prototype engine and multiple NodeJs projects. More information: http://www.faceop.com

### Used technologies (mobile, full-stack, db, testing & bug tracking)

Android Java (extensive Google APIs and maps usage, POIs, OAuth2 full implementation etc), XAMPP, Apache, GitHub, MEAN stack, ReactJS, MongoDB+Mongoose, SQLite & MySQL (Android), Eclipse, Java8, REST/CRUD, Spring & Spring-Boot, JUnit, TDD/BDD, MoreUnit, Mocha, Sonar Reports, Hudson, PMD, ECLEmma, JRebel etc.

### **Experience**

Aalto Protomo member, Protomo, Helsinki, Finland, 2013-2014 Government sponsored program for (Aalto Protomo) for entrepreneurship. Visioned and build an early prototype for an app for "meeting your yet unknown soulmates" (GPSMeet).

## Used technologies

XCode + Objective C, Appery.io cloud development (Javascript), Parse DB

#### **Experience**

# Software consultant, Perigeum Oy, Helsinki, Finland, 2008-2013

Served multiple international companies headquartered in Helsinki capital area. Included also internal education & projects at Perigeum's office related to big data (Hadoop) technologies.

Customer projects will be listed in appropriate details below. Some details are omitted due to NDAs.

### **Customer project**

Consultant, Itella Oy, Helsinki, Finland, 2008-2009

## Used technologies

Java, JSP, portals, XML & WSDL & web services, HTML + CSS

## **Customer project (under NDA)**

Consultant, NSN/Nokia, Helsinki, Finland, 2009-2010

### Used technologies

• Java (JEE), web services, Oracle WebLogic 8-10

### **Customer project**

Consultant, CGI, Helsinki, Finland, 2010 Used technologies

Java, Spring, Hibernate / JPA, scrum, JIRA, CI + DevOps

### **Customer project (remote)**

Consultant, CGI, Tampere/Helsinki, Finland, 2010

### Used technologies

Java, HTML + Javascript (form processing)

## **Customer project**

Consultant, OP-Pohjola, Helsinki, Finland, 2011 Used technologies

Java + Spring, Javascript + JQuery, HTML + CSS

## **Customer project**

Consultant, Vaisala Oy, Vantaa, Finland, 2011-2012

### **Project description**

Engineered a weather (precipitation etc.) condition monitoring applications for e.g. helipads (international end customer, NDA).

#### Used technologies

Java, Spring etc.

### **Experience**

Senior software engineer, Medicel Oy, Helsinki, Finland, 2003-2008 Created multiple tools and applications for processing and matching biochemical data and motifs, visualising data sets, gene ontologies and biochemical pathway navigation. Basically I was part of a team that built a massive integrator software to be used for rational drug research &

development. I created for example a mass spectrometry visualisation application which took mass spectrometry peak data as input and visualised it and allowed the user to further visually analyse the data within the application.

## Used technologies

 Oracle SQL, Eclipse & Java (JEE), cruise control, JBoss, JIRA, bug rat, unit testing, DevOps (CI)

### **Experience**

Software developer, Quartal Oy, Helsinki, Finland, 2001-2002

• Created financial software with Java, e.g. for a financial statement analyser.

#### **Experience**

Research assistant, computer science laboratory, Helsinki University of Technology, 1998-2000

### Description

Used Java and HTML to build applications for helping in learning computer science basics (CS course material).

### Education & academic status

Helsinki University of Technology (current Aalto university), MSc of computer science (96-03), eligible for phd studies, title of master's thesis: "An Intelligent Method for Visualizing and Navigating Biochemical Pathways" (grade: 4/5)

### **Skills**

Java 2-8 (JEE), Spring[MVC/Boot], Hibernate / JPA, REST / CRUD, DevOps (CI/CD), agile & scrum, project management, Javascript, NodeJS, MEAN-stack, ReactJS, C, Pascal, MC68k asm, Basic, unit testing (Java / Javascript), Selenium, Eclipse (since 2003), Hudson, Sonar reports, JIRA, mobile development (especially Android), software architecture, design patterns and modelling.

Ability to create software from an idea to production (e.g. to Google Play) according to the required coding conventions (e.g. linting). Team working and project coordination / management skills. Remote working experience.

My developer story since 1990: <a href="https://danielkolsi.github.io/docs/ds.html">https://danielkolsi.github.io/docs/ds.html</a>